This video is sponsored by Hatacon, one
of the best open-source platform to
monitor, debug and improve your
production ready large model
application. I was able to build this
MCP server where it will prompt user to
sign up, login and connect to cursor
automatically. And when user prompt
cursor to use this MCP, it will
dynamically generate a payment link
where it will ask for user credit card
and charge them by MCP usage and only
after user paid MCP will start working.
And the more user use your MCP and find
value, the more they will be charged.
And you can set up sophisticated usage
based tier to monetize your MCP server
properly. This is what I want to take
you through today. How to set up and
monetize your own MCP server and
distribute to thousands of people. So
MCP obviously is the hottest topic for
the past few months. It extends AI
agents capability to integrate different
type of systems or access external docs
easily. And the beauty of MCP from my
perspective is that anyone who has
domain knowledge can actually build MCP
to help agent complete specific tasks
and distribute to hundreds of thousands
of people. But one problem I see is that
most of those MCPS today are just
running locally on users machine. And
obviously the setup is quite technical
that made the distribution and
monetization of MCP awkward. It mostly
works for people who already use your
product. Otherwise, they will need to go
through it whole flow of go to your
website, sign up, pay, get API key, add
MCP server, and then start using. But
what really caught my attention is that
Stripe recently just released this agent
SDK where you can easily create a paid
MCP server by attaching a price ID and a
tools to achieve some similar experience
that I just showed you earlier. And that
really change how you distribute and
monetize MCP server. Now you can just
get start using right away and while
they are using it you can prompt them to
upgrade. So this will make building MCP
business much more interesting and this
is what I want to take you through today
and I will break that down into two
parts. One is how do we set up a payment
system for your MCP server by usage and
second is how do you set up a nice
authentication layer for your MCP server
and we're going to use three very useful
package. which one the stripe agent
toolkit that allow you to connect
payment very easily and cloudflare has
this MCP class you can just turn any
function right into a MCP tool and also
set up the OOS layer and in the end
we're going to use MCP remote which is
allow you to achieve this type of UX
that prompt user to create account and
sign in but before you launch your paid
MCP to the world how will you know if
your pricing strategy for your large
model product actually makes sense or if
users are secretly burning through your
API budgets this is where her headon is
such a game changanger manager. So,
Helicon is an all-in-one platform for
monitoring, debugging, and most
importantly, understanding how people
are actually using your large model
application. You get real-time
visibility into exactly how much each
user or endpoint is costing you down to
every single API call, prompt, and model
used. With this detailed cost and usage
analytics, you can see which feature are
driving your bill and where you might
need to adjust your pricing to. But it
goes way beyond just cost. It helps you
analyze how people are interacting with
your prompt which allow you to spotted
patterns and understand where you can
optimize and even get data sets so that
you can fine-tune your own model to
reduce cost while improving performance
and reliability. It has loads of super
useful functionalities like caching if
users are asked the same requests to
launch your model. It will just return
the result cach before so it doesn't
cost you anything and reduce latency.
They also have prompt experiments
feature where you can compare multiple
different prompts across thousands of
different real user requests. So you can
iterate your prompts with confidence. So
if you're building a paid MCP server or
any large language model powered app,
use headcom to monitor your cost,
understand your users and build a
business that actually scales. I have
put a link in the description below for
you to get start. Now without further
ado, let me show you how to build a paid
MCP server. So, Stripe has this agent
toolkit. They allow you to define an MCP
server and you can just add payment
gator tools by define the name, the
function as well as price ID. And with
this, you can set up quite sophisticated
pricing strategy. Either set up a
one-off pricing for lifetime access to
your awesome MCB server. But you can
also set up a recurring subscription as
well as usage based pricing, which is
probably the most interesting and
suitable one for MCP server where you
probably use different AI model behind
the scenes. And all those capabilities
can be achieved with just few lines of
code by using this paid MCP agent class
provided by stripe. So this paid MCP
agent class is a extended version of
Cloudflare's MCP agent class which is a
package that allow you to turn any
functions you build into a MCP2 very
easily. Let me take you through this MCP
agent very quickly so you understand the
fundamentals. Then we showcase some new
capabilities from this paid MCP agent
class. You can just open cursor in any
folder and do this. Create Cloudflare
test my MCP server template is
Cloudflare AI demo remote MCP oles and
inside source folder. This index ts is
how you can set up MCP server. So you
will use this class defined by
cloudflare called MCP agent. Give a name
version and then start adding tools like
a simple MCP tool for adding numbers
together or a bit more sophisticated
calculation. You can give it the name,
the type of input that this tool should
take and define the actual
functionalities. All you need to do just
pasting the name of MCP server the
URL/MCP. So this is how simple it is for
you to create your own MCP. And what
Strap did is basically have a new class
called paid MCP agent that is built
based upon Clawflar's MCP agent class.
So the setup is very similar. You can
still add public tools like what you did
before. But what you can do now is that
you can also add a paid tool and all you
need to do just passing on this
additional information which is price ID
the payment reason which will show up if
user haven't paid to explain why they
should upgrade and that's pretty much it
with this setup. If a user try to call
this specific MCB tool but they haven't
paid yet, it will return a result of the
payment link as well as a reason why
they need to pay. So the agent can
actually render and show this payment
link to the user. And as I mentioned
before, there are multiple different
ways you can set up payment strategy.
This example of how do you set up a
one-time payment. Just go to Stripe,
create a product, and the pricing will
be one off, give the price, then you
will get this pricing ID that you can
copy and paste over. You will need to
define a payment success, which is where
do you want to take users to after they
pay successfully. So you can create a
nice looking page that showing users
instruction about what to do next. So
this is a onetime payment. You can also
create a subscription payment where
setup is almost identical except the
pricing will be recurring and you can
set up flat rate fee here and pasting
over the price ID and the mode will be
subscription. But the most interesting
part is this usage based payment method
every time when user uses MCP tool. It
will record a usage and consumer
credits. You need to do is choose this
usage based pricing. The most common one
is probably per tier. So let's say you
want to set up a emoji generator MCP.
The first five generation will be free
per unit price will be zero and there's
no flat fee. After that you want to
charge $1 and it will give them some
credits to generate let's say 30 emojis.
You want to give a new tier which charge
$10 that gives them 500 credits. If they
exceed that 500 quota then you will
charge
0.001 per new emoji generated. So you
can create that but you will need to
attach a meter. You can search for meter
on stripe and then create a meter. Meter
is basically counter that keep track the
usage of the user. You can give a name
and choosing how you want this meter to
be added. You will choose that meter to
track the usage. Then you can just copy
this pricing ID over to the line item
here as well as meter event which is
this event name you can get from the
meter page and the mode will be still
subscription. So this setup will
automatically track the usage. So in
this example chat earlier I call this
MCP server 10 times and in the invoice
automatically track my usage and
calculate the invoice dynamically. So
this is how you can use stripe agent
toolkit to add pricing and payment to
your MCP server so you can start
monetize. If you want to get more in
depth step-by-step tutorial I have
detailed breakdown for how to build a
proper MCP server as well as template
that already have authentication and
payment built in. All those tutorial and
MCP template will be inside AI builder
club I'm building. I have put the link
in the description below. So if you're
interested, feel free to join. But apart
from that, you also need to set up
authentication system for the MCP
server. So user can sign up and track
their usage. So here we're going to use
two things. One is Cloudflare OS
provider. Another is a MCP remote
package. So to build authentication
system for your own MCP server, you
actually need to do something called
OOS. OS is a protocol that allow user to
grant access to certain client
application to the server data. For
example, you often will see things like
login with Google or login with
Facebook. That's kind of common use case
for OASP. But for MCP, we need to use
OAS because for MCP, you often just
build a server and it is designed to be
used in multiple different clients like
cursor, wing serve. And the way it work
is that when someone add your MCP server
to cursor, it will send a request to to
the MCP server to check if a user
already logging or not. If it's not
authorized, it'll open the browser, get
a O code and wait for user to login
successfully. And after that, it will
ping server to generate access code and
verify if user grant access. This flow
might feels a bit more complicated. But
the good thing is that Cloudflare
actually provides this OS provider class
that is automatically handling the
pipeline for this OS. All you need to do
just implement a actual signup flow and
put that logic inside the default
handler and you don't need to worry
about any other stuff. And if you check
the example ripple from stripe that's
exactly what they did. So in the
index.ts at top they were defined those
pay tools but at the bottom there's a OS
provider where the default handler is
app which is stored in this app.ts. So
inside app.ts it has this /authorized
endpoint and they just have this mock
authentication system that is always log
in true. So it will just always assume
that user login and they can go to the
approval directly by putting the email
and click approve. So to build actual
authentication layer you just need to
build your own authentication flow which
I will show you how to do very quickly
then replace logic
inside/auorize instead of always log in
you need to do the check does the user
actually login if not you show them a
signup page so this is cloudfare part
the second piece that you really need is
this package called MCP remote mcp
remote as I mentioned before is a
special package that help you mimic UX
where you will prompt user to login when
they try to connect your MCP server in
cursor cuz if you don't have that and
just do the normal connection it won't
be able to connect the system properly
because user hadn't given any
authentication user will have to go to
your application generate a API key and
pass on here but what MCP remote will do
is that you can just change the command
to MPX MCP remote and the URL endpoint
this will kind of mimic the experience
so when user try to add that it will
automatically open the browser and
prompt user to sign in and only after
user approve the MCP tools will show up
properly so with These two things
together you can achieve that experience
where it prompt user to log in they can
start using right away and for the first
time it will prompt user to give credit
card and upgrade and you will capture
the email address of every single users
who are interesting using your MCP
server and here's one quick example of
how I build the authentication system
based on stripe ripple I showed earlier
I use superbase as authentication system
creating new superbase project and if I
go to setting data API it will give me
this URL as well as anonymous key I just
need to change thedev.v vars which is
like EMV file for Cloudflare superbase
URL and key and service row key which is
this three items here then go to
authentications turn on the email
authentication and then go to emails to
set up the email templates they're going
to send to user when they try to create
account the approach I normally use is a
one-time password which is every time
when user put in the email address we
send them a six digits for one-time
password this one I found has best email
deliverability so I don't need to worry
about those email goes to users like
spam sandbox. So you can just change
this and add a token here and then click
save. Once you've done that, we just
need to create a superbase.ts which has
a function to set up a superbase client
and then a function to send onetime
password to the user and superbase
already have the predefined function to
handle everything. So you don't need to
worry about that too much as well as a
function to verify if the onetime
password is correct. And we also have a
session TS. This is to be used after
user sign once you want to remember that
they have been signed in. So they don't
need to keep doing this. So it has this
function called store sessions as well
as get sessions when user try to connect
server again and in app.ts TS you will
want to change the logic inside /
authorize and again / authorize is where
you will define the whole logic about
check if user login already if not it
will request onetime password verify it
the endpoint for verifying the onetime
password and the page where we're going
to show to users after they make a
payment successfully that's pretty much
it if you want to learn more I have
detailed breakdown of how to build a
proper MCP server with code example and
explanation so you can follow along copy
paste and plugin as as a paid MCP
template. They already have
authentication os flow and stripe
payment set up publicly. So you can just
take and launch your own paid MCP server
a few hours. All those tutorial and
templates is available in AI builder
cloud where we have a community of top
AI builders who are building and
launching their own AI products. So they
might already experience a problem and
challenge that you are facing today. You
can come and get advice as well as
in-depth course about AI coding and
building large model application from
myself and industry experts and we're
continuously providing more and more
useful tools to bootstrap your process
of building and launching AI products
from SAS templates and tank coder which
can help you generate effective PRD and
cursor rules and many other perks of
essential parts. If you're interested, I
have put a link in the description below
for you to click and join. I'm really
excited to see what type of MC you're
going to build. I hope you enjoy this
video and I see you next